AIYA MUKHAMEDSALOVA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END)

Innovative and creative Software Engineer with in excess of 4 years extensive experience in frontline development and testing of webbased applications. My strong background includes front-end development using HTML5, CSS3, SAAS/SCSS, JavaScript and React in addition to knowledge of version control systems such as SVN and Git, and a thorough understanding of object-oriented programming and design patterns.

EXPERIENCE

SEEK International

Software Engineer (Front-End)

Kuala Lumpur 10.2019 - Present

- Building Reusable component for multiple projects in React Js.
- Developing UI that meets the requirement from either mocks or prototypes.
- Have experience in Back-end using GraphQL and serverless.
- Manage structure for the front end code and bridge the gap between graphical designer and technical implementation.

SEEK International

Front-End Developer

Kuala Lumpur 11.2017 - 10.2019

- I have worked closely with internal Product and Marketing Teams, and external agencies when required, to deliver innovative features across all digital touchpoints, and produce concepts into fullyfunctional user-validated product, through the use of our CMS(HubSpot).
- In the midst of developing features in ReactJS for new platform on SRP pages to deliver increased website lead generation.
- I have worked with Product Designer and Marketing Team to commence solo development of two separate new landing page designs across both desktop and mobile, to be editable by Marketing Team.
- Owner of all HubSpot page, HubL and EDM technical development.

Link to Portfolio

Trusted Company

Front-End Developer

Kuala Lumpur 12.2016 - 11.2017

- I was involved in some projects for TrustedCompany to develop web based user interfaces using modern technologies using web 2.0 tools and technologies.
- I was assured that all user input is validated before submitting to
- My responsibilities included translation of the UI/UX design wireframes to actual code that will produce visual elements of the application.
- I worked with the UI/UX designer and bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation, taking an active role on both sides and defining how the application looks as well as how it works.

Link to Portfolio



CONTACT



+6 012 883 21 62



eaya94@gmail.com



http://aiya.icu



https://www.linkedin.com/in/aiya -mukhamedsalova-9865b412a/

SKILLS

Front-End:

- HTML and HTML5
- CSS, CSS3, Sass, Less, Styled Component
- Responsive Design
- JavaScript(ES5, ES6)
- React
- Redux
- jQuery
- Play Framework, AMP
- CMS (Wordpress, Drupal, HubSpot)
- Sketch App, Adobe Experience Design and Adobe Photoshop
- Responsive Frameworks (Bootstrap, Materlizecss)

Back-End:

- Serverless
- GraphQL
- Java

Miscellaneous

- NPM | Yarn
- Source Control (Git)
- CI/CD Automation (Buildkite)
- Unit & Integration Test (Jest, Enzyme and Cypress)
- Agile
- JIRA, Trello
- Microservices
- Design Patterns
- ESLint (Code Quality & Styles Issues)
- 3D Studio Max

Trusted Company

Junior Front-End Developer

Kuala Lumpur 08.2016 - 12.2016

- I worked in multidisciplinary team with other professionals such as back-end developers and web designers to provide high-quality graphics and visual elements.
- My duty was doing cross-browser compliant HTML/CSS and JavaScript.
- I made sure that the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs.
- I have managed the structure for the front end codes.

Link to Portfolio

AWARDS

NASA Space Apps Challenge 2019 - Top 10 out of 200
 Developed Mobile App using NASA data to create practical applications that support environmental and societal policy across water, health, food security and/or land use domains.

Link to Demo

TADHack Global Local Category - 2nd prize
 TADHack Local Category (Data Analytics) .Developed a platform
 that constantly analyze company data to identify how they can
 increase revenue.

Link to Demo

PLUS HACKATHON 2018: Hacking the Highway
 Build Mobile app that help people plan a trip

Link to Demo

- Entrance Scholarship (2013 2014)
 Swinburne University of Technology
- 1st place International Olympiad in Geography Paphos, Cyprus

PUBLIC SPEAKING

16.11.19 GDG Yogyakarta

• Topic: Accelerated Mobile Pages Project

05.04.19 Brown Bag in Seek Asia

• Topic: Kazakh girls in IT

02.06.20 GDG group Academy

• Topic: Journey from Non React to React

26.08.20 Webinar in Swinburne University of Technology

• Topic: Empowerment of Women in the Digital World

EDUCATION

2013-2016

Swinburne University of Technology

Bachelor of Information and Communication Technology

CERTIFICATIONS

ICAGILE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL

CONTRIBUTION

Women Tecmakers KL (WTM KL) Member

Women Who Code Member

Google Developer Group KL Member

Medium Blog

Effective Ways to Boost Landing Page Loading Speed

Volunteer for Hiring Squad at Seek

GITHUB

github.com/aiya94

REFERENCES

Andy McFarlane

Senior Product Manager at Seek Asia Email: andrewmcfarlane.ie@gmail.com

Mohsen Samoodi

Design Lead at Bonsey Jaden Email: mohsensamoodi@gmai.com